let questions=[
    { 
         id:1,
        question:"If Mr. Karan salary is increased by 18% and then decreased by 12%. Then, find the percentage of increase or decrease in salary.",
        answer:"3.84% increase",
        option:[
            "3.43% increase",
            "3.48% decrease",
            "3.84% increase",
            "4.43% decrease",
        ]
    },
    { 
        id:2,
       question:"When the price of flour was increased by 20%, a family increase its consumption in such a way that the expenditure on flour was only 44% more than before. If previously family consumes 50 kg flour monthly, find the new monthly consumption of the same family.",
       answer:"60 kg",
       option:[
           "37.5 kg",
           "70 kg",
           "78 kg",
           "60 kg",
       ]
   },
   { 
    id:3,
   question:"A man spends 15%, 20% & 25% of his monthly income on mutual funds, travelling & medicines respectively and remaining of the income on households. If the difference between expenditures on households & mutual funds is Rs. 16,800 then calculate his monthly income.",
   answer:"",
   option:[
       "Rs. 55,300",
       "Rs. 58,400",
       "Rs. 67,200",
       "Rs. 75,200",
   ]
},
{ 
    id:4,
   question:"Govind saves 20% of his income and the rest are spent, if his salary is increased by 25% and the expenditure of Govind also increases, then find the increase in % of his expenditure. If the new saving of Govind is 12% of his salary, ",
   answer:"37.5%",
   option:[
       "33.33%",
       "25%",
       "37.5%",
       "20%",
       
   ]
},
{ 
    id:5,
   question:"There are two numbers ‘x’ and ‘y’, where ‘x’ is greater than ‘y’. If 37.5% of ‘y’ is more than 25% of ‘x’ by 25% of the difference between ‘x’ and ‘y’, then find the ratio of ‘x’ and ‘y’.",
   answer:"5 : 4",
   option:[
       "5 : 4",
       "8:5",
       "9:2",
       "2:7",
   ]
},
{ 
    id:6,
   question:"Ram saves 15% of his income. His income is raised by 12%, but the saving remains the same. Find the hike in his expenditure.",
   answer:"14.12%",
   option:[
       "14.8%",
       "35.26%",
       "14.12%",
       "35.45%",
   ]
},
{ 
    id:7,
   question:"There are two candidates participated in an election. 10% voters did not cast their votes and 60 votes were found to be invalid. The winner got 47% votes of the total voters and won by 308 votes. Find the number of voters in the voting list.",
   answer:"6200",
   option:[
       "6300",
       "6200",
       "6700",
       "6500",
   ]
},
{ 
    id:8,
   question:"There were two candidates in an election. 10% of the total voters did not cast their votes whereas 5% of the casting votes were declared invalid. If the winning candidate received 50% votes of the total voters and won by 7250 votes, then find out the total number of Voters?",
   answer:"50,000",
   option:[
       "50,000",
       "40,000",
       "60,000",
       "80,000",
   ]
},
{ 
    id:9,
   question:"The weight of two persons Amit and Sumit is in the ratio 5 : 7. Sumit’s weight is increased by 20% and the total weight of Amit and Sumit together became 156kg with an increase of 30%. By what percent did the weight of Amit increase?",
   answer:"44%",
   option:[
       "44%",
       "46%",
       "42%",
       "41%",
   ]
},
{ 
    id:10,
   question:"A boy, after giving away 80% of his pocket money to one companion and 6% of the remainder to another, has 47 paise left with him. How much pocket money did the boy have in the beginning?",
   answer:"",
   option:[
       "Rs. 5",
       "Rs. 2.50",
       "Rs. 3",
       "Rs. 8",
   ]
},
]
  